Playtime is over now, humans.
（アザゼル）
人間ども
今度は お遊びなしだ
（シャリオス）
まさか… “神の鍵”を？
Are they coming for the God Key?!
The great Michael requested that I keep it safe!
あれは ミカエル様から
護(まも)るように言われたもの
They must not be allowed to have it!
絶対に渡してはならぬ！
So many of 'em!
（ファバロ）
なんて数だ…
おまっ…
Where were you?! And what the hell you sneaking off for?!
部屋 抜け出して
どこ行ってたんだ？
（アーミラ）
オヤジ！
My old man!
Huh?
オヤジに会ったの
I met my old man!
Uh, you could at least call him "Dad"...
いや だから
せめて“お父さん”って…
Wait a sec. You met whose dad?
ちょっと待て
誰の父ちゃんに会ったって？
My dad! For real!
私のお父さん！　うそじゃないよ
So, wait, your dad's right here in...
それって つまり この城…
I'm hungry!
おなかすいた
（ファバロ）
おわあ！
Listen when people are talking to you!
おまっ… 人の話を聞けよ！
I'm waiting for sunrises again
Rise up, rise up, rise up
Let me see the sun
Rage of Bahamut
People always say
"black or white," but the world is so gray
Even angels and demons were once the son of God I praised
temee no gen'in wa temee no naka kara
You're the catalyst for your own demise
zenbu hikurumete omae no saga
It's inherent to your being
kizuku koro ni wa mou you're in a coffin
But by the time you realize, you're in a coffin
It's too late if you want to do something
What the hell is wrong with me?
I can't remember what I wanted to be
Tick, tack, which is what I found
I can see the keys are scattered around
kono yoru ga aketemo nanika kawaru wake ja nee sa
Even though a new day dawns, nothing's gonna change
Yes, I know; yes, I know that I...
I'm the only one
who can save myself
I'll never forget
All I wanna be is me
（兵士）
城門 下ろせ～！
Lower the bridge!
（ジャンヌ）
遅いぞ
You're late.
My apologies.
（ラヴァレイ）
申し訳ありません
What shall we do, Saint Jeanne?
（ゴラン）
いかがいたします？　聖女
（ジャンヌ）
ゴランはセージ 投石隊と共に
第一外壁の防衛を
You will defend the first outer wall with the sage and catapult units.
Lavalley, you and the dragon riders will hold off intruders at the second wall.
ラヴァレイは
ドラゴンライダーたちと
第二外壁にて侵入を阻止せよ
I will remain here and protect the castle with His Majesty.
私は ここに残り
陛下と この城をお護りする
Understood!
Move out!
出陣！
（ファバロ）
アーミラ～！
Amira!
アーミラ！
Where'd she go now?
どこだよ…
（リタ）
いた
There he is.
（カイザル）
ファバロ！
Favaro!
（ファバロ）
おう 来たか
Oh, you're here.
Where's Lady Amira?
アーミラ嬢は？
What exactly happened?
一体 何があったのだ？
Apparently she met her old man and now she's brimmin' with energy.
どうも 親父(おやじ)さんに
会ったらしくて
テンション
上がっちまってんだ
父君に？　この城でか？
Her father?! Here in this castle?
（リタ）
それで
このありさまってわけね
Hence this, huh?
ぷはあ～
Satisfied now?
（ファバロ）
満足したか？
（アーミラ）
ハア…
ヒック
You're still eating?!
（ファバロ）
まだ食うのかよ！
Don't falter!
ひるむな！
We must prevent the demons' invasion at all costs!
悪魔の侵入を
何としても防ぐのだ！
しまった！
Oh, no...
（ラヴァレイ）
放て～！
Release!
Annoying pests.
（アザゼル）
こざかしい
やはり やっかいなのは あの女か
Seems like she's the only one who poses any real danger.
Leave her to me.
（パズズ）
俺に任せろ
しくじるなよ
Don't screw it up.
（パズズ）
フン！
You're not going anywhere!
行かせるか！
くっ… 橋が…
The bridge!
It's time for you to learn, scum.
（パズズ）
思い知らせてやるよ ゴミども
人間の力とやらが
Time for you to learn just how meager the so-called power of humans is!
どれほど ちっぽけかをなあ！
No, no, no, no, no!
（アーミラ）
やだ やだ やだ やだ やだ～！
I'm not done eating!
まだ食べる～！　放せ～！
Let go!
（ファバロ）
いいかげんにしやがれ
この酔っ払いが！
You've had enough already, you boozehound!
（カイザル）
あなたは狙われているんです！
Your life is in peril! We need to get you to a safe place!
早く身を隠さないと…
てえっ… ああ…
たくよお
Man...
（ファバロ）
まるっきりガキだな
She acts like a kid!
Is she really even aware of the situation?
（リタ）
この子 ホントに自覚あるのかしら
Huh?
昼間の天使たちの言葉どおりなら…
If those angels today were right...
（ミカエル）
バハムートの復活は
何としても阻止せねばならぬ
We must prevent Bahamut's revival at all costs.
Keep the God Key safe, O valiant ones!
勇猛なる者たちよ
神の鍵を護るのだ
I assume that's what this raid is for.
（リタ）
この襲撃は そのせいでしょ？
You're probably right.
（ファバロ）
だよな
What's the plan, Favaro?
（カイザル）
どうする？　ファバロ
とにかく 今は こいつを
どっかに かくまわねえとな
For now, we gotta get her somewhere safe.
Too late.
（アザゼル）
もう遅い
You!
（カイザル）
貴様は…
So it is him!
（ファバロ）
やっぱ こいつ…
人間ども
Now, then.
Be good little humans and hand over the God Key.
おとなしく 神の鍵を渡せ
We refuse!
断る
Oh, is that your so-called "chivalry" talking?
（アザゼル）
騎士の精神というやつか？
You're as naïve as your father was.
父親同様 愚直だな
How do you know my father?
なぜ 私の父を知っている？
絞首台に送り込んだのが
俺だとしたら
What if I told you I was the one who sent him to the gallows?
どうする？
I remember it well.
（アザゼル）
覚えているぞ
お前の父に浴びせられた
The countless jeers...
いくつもの罵声を
Showered upon your father...
“騎士の恥さらしにも程がある！”
"'Disgraceful' doesn't even begin to describe the knight you are!"
Oh, the hateful insults they all spewed at him...
誰もが
侮蔑を込めて なじっていたな
It was you?
貴様… が？
Those magic stones were mine, actually.
あの魔石は もともと俺の物だ
I had considered it an amusing way to pass the time.
暇潰しの戯れと思っていたが
いやいや なかなかに面白い…
I must say, though, the manner in which he died...
was most entertaining.
（ラウルス）
死に様だったよ
Listen up, small fry.
（ファバロ）
いいか 三下(さんした)
１つ忠告しといてやる
Here's a bit of info for ya.
The guy who got Kaisar's old man killed...
こいつの親父の敵(かたき)は
この俺だ
was me!
You?
敵だと？
ファバロ なぜ…
Favaro! Why are you...
Do me a favor, Kaisar.
（ファバロ）
頼まれてくんねえか カイザル
Take Amira and get out of here.
アーミラ連れて 逃げろ
Bring her to Helheim for me.
そんで
ヘルヘイムに連れてってやってくれ
Go on.
行けよ
こいつは悪魔同士の戦いだ！
This is a fight between two demons!
Favaro!
ファバロ！
Let's go!
行くわよ！
悪魔同士と言ったか？
Between demons, you say?
Seize the God Key.
神の鍵を捕らえろ
Hey! That ain't fair!
（ファバロ）
ちょい… ずりいぞ お前！
悪魔だからなあ
I am a demon.
What's the matter?
（パズズ）
どうした？
Had enough already, human?
もう終わりか 人間ども
フンッ
（パズズ）
気に食わねえな
Not that I really care at all,
but your bravado ends now!
だが その強がりも おしまいだ！
Time for you to die!
とっとと くたばりやがれ！
Saint Jeanne!
（騎士）
聖女様！
Too easy.
（パズズ）
たわいもねえ
来い！　マルテ！
Come, Maltet!
Impossible!
（パズズ）
バカな…
（ジャンヌ）
闇の眷属(けんぞく)よ
Bow before my sacred power, kin of darkness!
聖なる力の前に屈するがいい
Oh! Saint Jeanne is truly unmatched!
（騎士Ｂ）
やはり ジャンヌ様こそ…
What's so funny?!
何が おかしい？
I wouldn't count this as a victory if I were you.
（パズズ）
勝ったなどと思わないことだ
As we speak, the God Key is...
今頃 神の鍵は…
まさか…
No!
Jeanne!
ジャンヌ
Lavalley...
ラヴァレイか…
Are you injured?!
おけがは？
I'm fine.
大丈夫だ
More importantly, the key girl...
それよりも鍵の娘を…
Understood.
承知しました
だあっ！
Of all the times...
こんなときに限って…
どんなものかと思ってみれば
Just when I thought you might prove to be a challenge...
I believe I'll go and take the God Key now.
そろそろ
神の鍵を頂戴しに行くとしよう
Kaisar!
（ファバロ）
カイザル！
I swiped it earlier with the intention of using it on you sometime.
（カイザル）
いつか お前に食らわせてやろうと
失敬しておいた
I guess some knights have sticky fingers too!
（ファバロ）
手癖の悪(わり)い騎士もいたもんだ
Where's Amira?
アーミラは？
Never fear.
心配ない
Why'd you come back, anyway?
（ファバロ）
大体 何しに戻ってきたんだよ？
For vengeance.
（カイザル）
敵討ちだ
Huh?
父の敵を
I can't let this demon take my father's killer, after all.
あの悪魔に
譲るわけにはいかないからな
Oh, that's right! You're that thief's son!
そうだったな！
お前 あの盗賊の息子だったな
面白い！　面白すぎるぞ
This is great! Hilarious, even!
自分が敵になることで
So, you gave him a reason to live by making yourself his sworn enemy?
そいつに生きがいを
与えてやったというわけか？
What a incredibly touching tale.
（アザゼル）
実に泣かせる話じゃないか
弱くてね この手の話に…
I have a soft spot for such tearjerkers.
In that case, that would make me both of your fathers' killers.
だとすれば
お前たち２人の父の敵は
この俺というわけだ
Very well! I'll play with you!
（アザゼル）
いいだろう！　つきあってやるぞ
I finally have something to whet my appetite!
ようやく そそられる肴(さかな)が出てきた
Don't be gettin' the wrong idea!
（ファバロ）
勘違いしてんじゃねえよ
My old man died 'cause he screwed up.
親父はヘマして おっ死(ち)んだだけだ
Vengeance? Giving Kaisar a reason to live?
敵討ちだ？
カイザルの生きがいだ？
I don't give a damn about that!
I'm me! To hell with living a life of revenge.
俺は俺だ
復讐(ふくしゅう)に縛られた生き方なんざ
まっぴら御免だ
I live for myself!
俺は俺のために生きる
Favaro...
ファバロ…
You're not my sworn enemy or anything else.
（ファバロ）
てめえは敵でも何でもねえ
You're nothing but a putrid demon!
ただの いけすかねえ悪魔だ
人間風情が…
Lowly human...
私には 私の
I see. I have my way of life, and you have yours.
お前には お前の生き方か…
You always have to embellish everything, dontcha?
いっつも大げさなんだよ おめえは
性分なんでな
That's just how I am.
In that case...
おらあ！
また目くらましか
Another smoke screen, I see.
However...
だが…
カイザル！
Kaisar!
Perhaps you should be more worried about yourself.
人の心配をしている場合か？
This is the end.
終わりだ
意外に使えんじゃねえか
I'm pretty good with this, huh?
Curse you!
貴様…
Like I said, this fight...
言ったろ　悪魔同士の…
is between us demons!
戦いだって！
契約魔法ごときで調子に乗るな
Don't let a measly contract spell get to your head!
（カイザル）
いや…
No...
This is a fight between demon and human!
人間と悪魔の戦いだ
２人の人間と悪魔のな！
Two humans and one demon, to be precise!
Did that kill him?!
（ファバロ）
やったか？
Just kidding.
なんてな
（アザゼル）
残念だが
俺は人間の武器では殺せない
Sorry, but human weapons cannot kill me.
It seems that good-for-nothing has failed me after all.
やはり しくじったか
役立たずめ
No matter. I will kill you two here and now.
まあいい
お前たちは ここで俺が殺してやる
Crap!
やっべ…
何か いい手はねえか？
There's gotta be some way to deal with this bastard!
あの野郎…
I've changed my mind.
（カイザル）
気が変わった
Huh?
You should take her to Helheim, Favaro.
（カイザル）
ヘルヘイムへは… ファバロ
お前が連れていけ
Prepare to join your father!
父のもとへ行け！
Kaisar!
カイザル～！
I have one thing to share with you, too.
（カイザル）
私も １つ忠告させてもらう
You aren't my father's killer.
貴様は父の敵ではない
賞金首ですらない
You aren't even a bounty hunter.
You're just a mere demon.
ただの悪魔… だ…
にん… にん…
人間どもがあああ！
Y-Y-You wretched humans!
ハア…
We are victorious, Your Majesty!
（参謀）
陛下！　我らの勝利です
（シャリオス）
ハア… 助かった
What a relief.
やりましたな 聖女
We did it, Saint Jeanne!
Those two bounty hunters...
What are their names again?
あの２人の賞金稼ぎ
名は何といったか？
Huh?
Favaro...
ファバロ…
バカ野郎…
Kaisar, you dumbass...
カイザル てめえ 早くしろお～
Hurry it up!
Right.
Amira. Wake, Amira.
（ラヴァレイ）
アーミラ…
起きなさい アーミラ
F-Father?
（アーミラ）
お… とう… さん？
ハア…
終わったわよ
It's over.
Now wake up alrea—
いいかげん起きなさい…
My destiny,
sotto oshiete hoshii
won't you tell me?
aenai
But you're gone
ima wa tooi place to be
in a place so far away
unmei wa kawaru to
"Fate changes"
oshietekureta the truth is free
That's what you told me, and now the truth is free
I miss you
I revere you
You're my everything
I will follow you
subete wa ano toki
It all began then
To the promised land
tsuretette
So take me
yakusoku no basho e
to the promised land
Father?
（アーミラ）
お父さん？
お父さん どこ？
Where are you, Father?
（ハンサ）
どうしたんですか？
What's the matter?
（バッカス）バカヤロー
（ハンサ）くわ？
You idiot...
（バッカス）アヒルのバカヤロー！
（ハンサ）アヒルじゃありません！
You dumbass duck!
I am not a duck!
（バッカス）何か言え！
（ハンサ）くわっ！
Nonsense!
On the next Rage of Bahamut: Genesis,
"Beyond the Storm"!
（ハンサ）
次回「神撃(しんげき)のバハムート GENESIS(ジェネシス)」
Beyond(ビヨンド) the(ザ) Storm(ストーム)
（バッカス）バカヤロー！
（ハンサ）なんで？
You're an idiot!
Why?
Illustration: Soji Hisakata
Let's Bahamut to the max again next week!